

+353-899436911 | dasari.shilpa05@gmail.com

# SHILPA DASARI

Sandyford, Dublin 18 - Holding Stamp 1G Visa - Available Immediately <u>www.linkedin.com/in/shilpa-dasari</u>

### **SUMMARY**

Information Technology graduate with six years experience as a Business Intelligence Developer in Tata Consultancy Services. A strong team-player dedicated to expanding and deepening my technical knowledge in order to deliver on my employer's objectives and develop as a professional. Currently focused on building my DevOps knowledge with a view to gaining practical experience in this area. A participant in the Skillnet ReBoot program and eager to return to a technical role in the workplace.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE**

- Six years experience in Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence technologies like **Cognos** and **SAP BO**.
- Sound knowledge of Cognos Report Studio, Framework Manager, Event studio, Query studio.
- Good understanding of **DevOps** concepts.
- Familiar with Cloud based services like **AWS Ec2, IAM**.
- Familiar with installing and configuring **Jenkins CI tool** on Centos/Linux OS.
- Knowledge in developing CI/CD Pipelines.
- Hands-on experience using Version Control Management Tool like GIT and its web repositories in Git hub for source code storage and management.
- Good knowledge on installation of Jenkins, GIT, Launching EC2 instance using Ansible playbook.
- Good knowledge in Tableau.
- Strong Data visualizations skills; created worksheets using Bar Chart, Area Map using Show Me functionality and created filters, parameters and calculated columns for preparing worksheets.
- Strong in proactively identifying, analysing, reporting and solving faults.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

### **Technology Ireland Software Skillnet**

**July 2020** 

National tech sector initiative designed to help address skills shortages in the Tech workforce.

# **Women ReBOOT Program participant**

Selected for this intensive, highly interactive program which allowed me to refresh and update my technical and professional skills. It also provided an overview of the current technical landscape and marketplace.

# Accomplishment:

- As part of a team, proposed and presented the Health Box web application in Dragon's Den Pitch. Health Box is a cloud-based repository which stores the medical history of patients in digital format.
- It was well received by the audience with feedback that it was a good idea and that there was demand for such a product on the Irish market.

Career Break 2018- 2020

In 2018, I took a parental break and joined my spouse who was working in Ireland.

During this period, I also dedicated time to refreshing my skills and training in new technologies.

- Recently trained in DevOps.
- Trained and Certified in Tableau.

# Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

2011-2017

### **Cognos Developer**

Worked on different migration projects like Cognos 7 to 10, SAP BO to Cognos 10.

- Documented and analysed user requirements.
- Created metadata models using framework manager.
- Analysed the complexity of reports first and then started with development.
- Created list, Cross tab reports, Chart Reports, Tabbed Reports using Report Studio.
- Created reports using Conditional Formatting and Conditional style.
- Developed complex reports with drill through capabilities, summarization, grouping and filtering.
- Maintained weekly and monthly schedules using Event Studio.
- Implemented standards in Report design and appearance by following set of predefined rules to the report structure.
- Optimized report performance by handling calculations at model in Framework Manager instead of report level in report studio.
- Experience in debugging SQL queries particularly related to Cognos Report performance issues.
- Validated the reports as part of unit testing against checklist before release to QA team.

### Accomplishments:

- Awarded "Emerging Team Player Award" in 2012.
- Awarded "Spotlight Award" in 2016.
- Awarded "Best Team Player Award" in 2017.
- Received appreciation from senior management for on time delivery of the project.
- Received appreciation from the client for suggesting and implementing Tabbed Report concept, the impact of which was a reduction in the number of reports.

### **EDUCATION**

Bhoj Reddy Engineering College for Women, JNTU, INDIA - Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology (2006 – 2010)

# **TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS**

- Extensive self-study of Dev/Ops.
- Tableau Desktop Specialist Certified.
- IBM Certified Designer Cognos 10 BI Reports
- IBM Certified Developer Cognos 10 BI Metadata Models Certification.

### **INTERESTS**

Cooking, Gardening